## **Matthew Pearson**

Romford RM1 Mobile: 07955 803999

Email: matt.pearson29@googlemail.com

## PERSONAL PROFILE

A confident and reliable IT support engineer with extensive practical experience of working with computers and resolving any support issues that are raised. Possessing a proven ability to administer and control the operation, configuration and maintenance of computer-based information systems, as well as having an eye for detail and able to multi-task under pressure. Have the flexibility for working well as part of a team and solo.

## KEY SKILLS AND COMPETENCIES

- Excellent problem-solving skills and awareness of electrical safety issues
- Knowledge of operating systems, hardware and software
- Analytical skills to find and fix problems
- The ability to explain technical problems in everyday English
- Excellent customer service skills
- Organisational and time-management skills

#### AREAS OF EXPERTISE

- Full stack web developer
- Computer hardware help-desk ticket systems cabling
- Routers cisco/drevtek switches wireless Wi-Fi
- TCP/IP v4/v6 DNS DHCP GPO

- Ms windows Ms Servers Active Directory RRAS
- IIS Linux distros Linux Servers Apple Mac
- Citrix Ms office 365 Android IOS
- Remote access VPN's Vlan FTP/SFTP
- ssh Apache DOS BASH

## SUPPORTING SKILLS AND EXPERIENCE

- Installing new IT systems to meet security regulations.
- Upgrading existing hardware, software and networks.
- Documenting systems so others can provide ongoing support.
- Setting up new pc's for people and training staff.
- Carrying out on-site maintenance to prevent future problems.
- Logging and prioritising faults and queries.
- Fixing faulty equipment and testing systems.
- Putting back-up systems in place.
- Maintaining IT equipment.
- Deleting rootkits and embedded viruses.
- Scrapping of unwanted IT equipment.
- Organising emails and liaising with colleagues.
- Monitoring platforms to check connections.
- Dealing with phone systems and power supplies.
- Supporting virtual platforms and servers.

## **EMPLOYMENT HISTORY**

Jan 2020 – Presant	Trainning to be a full stack web developer	
2018 - 2019	First stop IT	IT Engineer 2nd line
2016 - 2018	Romford Drivers Association	Telephonist/ IT Technician
2013 - 2016	The Cloud Network	Field Service Engineer
2011 - 2013	Morgan	College Tutor
2005 - 2011	<b>Barking and Dagenham Council</b>	Plant Operator
2003 - 2005	E-planet	<b>Networking Team Leader</b>
2000 - 2003	Ultimate IT	Network Engineer
1999 - 2000	S B E International	<b>Electronics Engineer</b>

# **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

Full stack web developer (Html/Html5, CSS/CSS3, Bootstrap, Java script, Jquerry, API's, Github/Git, Heroku, Python, Flask, Django, Sql/ No Sql Data bases).

- Diploma in IT
- MCP Microsoft Server NT Four
- MCP Microsoft Workstation Four
- TCP/IP
- MCP Microsoft Server 2000
- MCP Microsoft 2000 Professional
- CISCO CCNA
- Sophos Certified Engineer